

C O N T A C T

- Home Address: Goodwood Cape Town, South Africa 7460
- christian1.raymond@gmail.com
- https://christiangubana.github.
- **in** @christian-ngubana

LANGUAGES&TECHNO LOGIES

- ••• HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript/ES6+
- • • ReactJS/ReduxJS/ExpressJS
- ••• Docker/TailwindCSS/TDD
- •••• NodeJS/MongoDB/Sass/Ruby
- ••• Monday.com/CI,CD/JiraCloud
- • Bootstrap/Git/RESTful API's

SOFT SKILLS

- Time Management / Team work
 / Excellent communication
 skills
- Critical thinking & Problem Solving / Public speaking
- Adaptability / Self starting & Mentoring

CHRISTIAN NGUBANA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a software developer with a strong passion for problem-solving. I have indepth experience building software products that help organizations address business challenges and meet their needs. I care about writing high-quality software that delivers bespoke products and services.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Injozi Digital | Jan 2023 - Present

Responsible for turning wireframes and mock-ups into reusable code and building high-quality UI components with high-quality, and scalability. Develop features with web development best practices.

Collaborate with teams and stakeholders across the organization to discuss the needs, design, and functionality of the project. Debug errors, troubleshoot issues, and perform routine performance optimizations.

Frontend Developer

Platform45 | Nov 2021 - Oct 2022

Helped my team develop high-quality software.

Built beautifully designed digital products for both international and local clients, optimized UI/UX processes, and accessible across a broad range of platforms.

Identified areas for modification in existing programs and subsequently developed these modifications, consulted and worked closely with crossfunctional teams to gather requirements.

Project at https://pricebeater.app/

Built a dynamic secure and user-friendly data management web app that allows a URL to be sent out to users, this involves user registration on a back-end integrated third-party REST API, with a highly secured authentication process.

In the record, products get assigned to successfully registered users, and, a notification gets sent to the admin section for approval.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

COURSE

CS50 | HARVARD UNIVERSITY | MAY 2019

CODEX | CAPE TOWN SOUTH AFRICA

Certificate in Software Development | Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

- Exclusive Software engineering program (40% acceptance rate), Full-stack agile software development curriculum to JavaScript, Node.js, Express.Js, Ajax, HTML & CSS, DOM, Git&GitHub, Handlebars, MySQL, TDD(Mocha, Chai) Deployment: Heroku, Digital Ocean.
- Heavy concentration in data structures, Algorithm architecture, critical thinking & problem-solving using technologies.

TOGETHER TECHNOLOGIES BOOTCAMP | CAPE TOWN

Certificate in Software Development | Feb 2016 - Jan 2017

- Studied computer systems and software development
- Courses completed: Ruby Programming, Mastering Ruby Blocks & Iterators, Ruby on Rails: Level 1, Ruby on Rails: Level 2, Ruby on Rails Tutorial: 3rd Edition, BDD with Ruby on Rails using RSpec 3 and Capybara, HTML & CSS, Git, virtualization/cloud technologies deployment to GitHub, Heroku.
- Built a mock customer service web app that solved real-life problems.

CPUT | CAPE TOWN SOUTH AFRICA Civil Engineering | 2014

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

TA Member at RailsBridge Cape Town | July 2016 - Present

I care deeply about diversity and inclusion in the tech industry and in the work we do. I co-organize and mentor at https://railsbridgecapetown.org/, we offer a free introduction to coding concepts, the available tools, Rails, Ruby, and JavaScript, HTML, CSS. It's specifically offered to groups of people that are underrepresented in tech, I practically spend my time in guiding and mentoring at the workshop while constantly communicating and troubleshooting the nature of problems to our new coders.

References

Jeremy Ramos: Senior lead Engineer at Platform45 jeremy@platform45.com: +27 78 642 5850

Thato Maloka: Senior Engineer manager at Injozi Digital

thato@injozi.biz: +27 73 954 8248